# **Dian Adriansyah**

## **Applications Developer**

Experience as Product Owner & Front End, Able to be collecting and transform the requirement into blueprint/ solution design. Work with developer's team and work multi-task/or multi-project. Ability to develop and detailed plan in software development. Implemented SCRUM methodology to drive agile project management, resulting in a 20% increase in team productivity and on-time delivery of 15+ client projects.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **Product Owner**

Maret 2018 - April 2022

PT Mitra Integrasi Informatika on site PT Jasamarga, Jakarta

- Translate ERP business needs into functional requirements and prioritize according to business value.
- Working with SCRUM make the product backlogs, facilitate daily scrum, sprint planning, sprint demo, and retrospective meetings.
- Streamlined internal communication channels and facilitated cross-functional collaboration, resulting in a 25% increase in on-time delivery of release/sprint goals.
- Lead the planning of product release plans and set the expectation for delivery of new functionalities, manage team, help identify and remove impediments, and resolve conflicts.
- Collaborate with team to create FSD, UAT, User Guide, Lo-fi/Hi-fi Mockup, and timeline.

## **Front End Developer**

Mai 2022 - Present

PT Mitra Integrasi Informatika on site PT Jasamarga, Jakarta

- Working with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, to create user interface from hi-fi mockup become responsive web.
- Using versioning GIT to Collaborate with back-end developer and integrated from backend developer with Rest API
- Collaborate with the development team to design, implement, and maintain the user interface and user experience of web applications.
- Working with SCRUM team methodology to develop applications.

#### **ORGANISATION EXPERIENCE**

- KMTI UMY (Keluarga Mahasiswa Teknologi Informasi) as Head of Public Relation Division 2014 - 2016
- BEM FT UMY (Badan Eksekutif Mahasiswa Fakultas Teknik) Division Kastrad (Kajian dan Strategi) as Member 2015 - 2016
- KMPK LS Yogyakarta (Keluarga Mahasiswa Kalianda Lampung Selatan) Head of division PSDM (Pengembangan Sumber Daya Mahasiswa) 2015-2017
- AERIAL TEAM TI UMY (Drone Club Study) Pilot DJI Phantom 3, 2015 2017

#### CONTACT

- driansyahsaputra@gmail.com
- +62821-3547-5864
- github.com/driansyahsaputra
- adrianwebportfoliosaputr.co.id

#### **SKILLS**

#### Technology:

- SDLC (SCRUM)
- Balsamiq Mockup
- Visual Studio Code
- Figma
- Visio
- Jira
- Miro
- GitHub
- Postman
- Consume Rest API

#### Tools and Programming:

- HTML
- CSS
- Bootstrap
- JavaScript
- Laravel
- jQuery
- Ajax
- Flutter
- React
- MySQL
- Postgres.

### **EDUCATION**

Universitas Muhammadiyah Yogyakarta - Information Technology 2013-2017

#### **TRAINING**

- SCRUM by Duta Academy 2018
- UI Design Mobil and Mobile by Rubrik Grafi, 2021
- Software Engineering by NIIT Academic, 2015 - 2018